Amit Biswas

iOS Developer



SUMMARY

6 Years of Object-Oriented Programming experience, expertise in Swift, Objective-C, C/C++. I have written 5+ iOS apps using Swift, UIKit, SpriteKit, AVFoundation, AirKit, MapKit, as well as various Cocoapods for 3rd party libraries. Striving to stay on top of the mobile technology while keeping up with ever-changing iOS development and loving every minute of mobile engineering.

EXPERIENCE

MazeGeek - Astoria, NY (www.mazegeek.com)

Feb 2016 - Present

Software Engineer, iOS

Learning by doing, working in a diverse team, shipping real-world products. Collaborating and subcontracting with other developers to ensure enterprise-level code and products

- Vinndo -(Swift 4, Xcode 10, FirebaseMessasing, Firebase, Google MapSDK, ToastSwift, SwiftyJSON, IQKeyboardManager)
 Designed, built and deployed a rapid, on-demand automotive parts finding application in collaboration with Vinndo iOS development team.
- ScopePrice (Swift 4.2, Xcode 10, Cocoapods,SwiftyJSON,NVActivityIndicatorView,SideMenu, BarcodeScanner, AWSAPIGateway,,Alamofire, SwiftyJSON, Google Map SDK, IQKeyboardManager) ScopePrice is a web application which specializes in affiliate marketing and serves its users by providing price comparison for a huge portfolio of products from various suppliers.
- Keeno (Swift 4.2, Xcode 10.2,ObjectMapper, Social network Kit, SDWebImage ,Firebase, Google Map SDK, Sketch, Alamofire, SwiftyJSON, Rest API's ...)
 Keeno is a buying and selling app. Users can buy and sell products within the community by using the chat option. Promote your product & earn money through building a vast network.
- MotoMez (Swift, Xcode, Cocoapods, Sketch, Alamofire, SwiftyJSON, Rest API's ...)
 Developed a fully functioning warehouse inventory app which is used for back and forth inhouse shipment tracking and capable to scan product barcode as well.

Easy Alliance – Boston, MA Dec 2014 –Nov 2015

Web Developer

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript MySQL, Git , Gitlab, Vim.

Designed and developed roadmap for the web application which were stands for the User accessibility system. Maintained internal web tools for MySQL database backup and migration. Gather requirements in a weekly scrum and main stories. Weekly release and code reviews.

SKILLS

Languages: Swift ,Objective-C ,C, C++, JavaScript

Development Technologies: Xcode, UlKit, AirKi.t, WebKit, AVFoundation, Test Flight, CoreData, Firebase, GCD, ARC, Parsing JSON, Sketch App, Git, Cocoa touch, CocoaPods, CoreML, CoreGraphics, CoreMotion, MapKit, MVC, Instruments, AWS, Ebay Web Service, RESTful APIs, Linux Server Configuration, MapKit, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Vim ...

EDUCATION

Thomas Edison State University, Bachelor Of Computer Science (Remote)

Sep 2018-Sep 2019

Bangladesh University, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Feb 2011 -Dec 2012

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

ONLINE COURSES

Udacity Devslopes, Raywenderlich, Udemy, Linkedin Learning

AFFILIATIONS

Institute Of Electrical and Electronics Association ACM - Association For Computer Machinery New York Entrepreneurs & Startup Network MSP - Microsoft Student Partner September 2015 November 2015 November 2016 - Present May 2011 - Dec 2012